Matthew Curran

Email: <u>five3183@gmail.com</u> | Phone: 845-422-1708

Github: github.com/five3183 | Portfolio: www.matthewcurran.tech

Summary

Coding bootcamp graduate with a new-found passion for building web applications. Over 10 years of professional experience with a proven history of technical mastery. Developed critical thinking, analytical, reasoning and problem-solving skills. Talented in handling multiple projects while exceeding quality standards. Seeks an entry level position as a junior developer.

Technical Skills

• HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Materialize, jQuery, Ajax, Express, Node, MySQL, Mongo, Firebase, Handlebars, Angular, React, GIT, GitHub, OOP

Education

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT | SEP 2018 | UNC CHARLOTTE

• An intensive 6-month program dedicated to designing and building web applications.

B.S. PSYCHOLOGY | MAY 2012 | SAINT THOMAS AQUINAS COLLEGE

- Psi Chi Honor Society
- 3.78 GPA

A.A. LIBERAL ARTS | MAY 2010 | ROCKLAND COMMUNITY COLLEGE

- Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society
- 3.9 GPA

Applications Built

PERSONAL PRESCRIPTION PLANNER

- This app is designed to track user medications and alert them via text message to take them. After adding a medication to your prescription list, the app will query a drug database and check for possible conflicts. Text message alerts will be sent to the user to remind them to take medications.
- This is a react app, with a node.js/express server and uses mongo for the database. Text messaging is powered by Twilio, news
 feed by newsapi.org. NPM packages include axios, moment, bcryptjs, cheerio, cron, dotenv, mongoose, passport, and validator.
- Website: https://personal-prescription-planner.herokuapp.com
- GitHub: https://github.com/taw1313/team-merge-p3

NOPE!

- This is app allows users to add restaurants to the map, write reviews and update busy status. Icons on the map will be displayed in either red or green depending on the busy status of the restaurant.
- This is a multi-page app that has an node.js/express server and uses mongo for a database. The map canvas and geocoding are powered by google api.
- Website: https://frozen-plateau-24963.herokuapp.com
- GitHub: https://github.com/five3183/NOPE2.0

THE CLICKY GAME

- This is a game where the player selects a unique image. After every selection the images will shuffle. Clicking on the same image twice will end the game. Select 12 unique images in a row to win.
- This is a react app.
- Website: https://calm-bastion-93483.herokuapp.com
- GitHub: https://github.com/five3183/clicky

Experience

INSIDE AUTO ADJUSTER | ALLSTATE INSURANCE COMPANY | 2015 - 2018

Negotiated auto insurance claims with repair facilities and customers. Researched and compiled auto repair blueprints adhering to industry standards. Efficiently handled 8 to 11 auto claims per day. Periodically lead team meetings, trained and mentored coworkers. Continually exceeded quality goals by 5% and production goals by 25%.

ASSISTANT MANAGER | B&B AUTO BODY | 2009 - 2014

Tracked vehicles repairs ensuring low repair cycle time. Performed quality control checks during and after repairs. Ensured that proper repair methods were being followed. Assembled and disassembled vehicles. Used scan tools to diagnose, and clear trouble codes.

FIRE TEAM LEADER | US ARMY | 2004 - 2009 (STATE AND OVERSEAS ASSIGNMENTS)

Alpha team leader responsible for a 4-person fire team and maintenance and accountability of all team equipment. Lead combat patrols during Operation Iraqi Freedom. Subject matter expert on all assigned weapon systems. Combat Infantry and Expert Infantry Badge recipient.